Mouad ZIANI Fullstack Software Engineer

**** 212 654 899 763

mouad.ziani1997@gmail.com

in mouad-ziani

mouadziani

PROFILE

I'm Fullstack Software Engineer on web ecosystem, Final year Master degree student specialised in Computer System Engineering and passionate about software engineering, with strong background in PHP, Javascript/Typescript, Java and Python.

I have over +3 years of experience at private IT companies. Also as a freelancer.

EDUCATIONS

2019 - present Master's degree (M2), Computer Systems Engineering

Benimellal, Morocco University Sultan Mulay Suliman

2018 – 2019 Bachlor's degree in Cs (Web programming And Technologies)

Marrakesh, Morocco University Cadi Ayyad, Faculty of Sciences Semlalia

Promotion Major

2015 - 2017 Specialized technician diploma, Software Development

Laayoune, Morocco Higher Institute of Management and Computer Sciences

Promotion major

2015 Baccalaureate in Physical Sciences

Laayoune, Morocco Mohammed V High School

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

09/2020 - present

Remotely

Fullstack Software Engineer

Promy.fr 🛮

Tech Stack:

- Back end: PhP7, Laravel, Rest APIs, MySQL.
- Front end: Vuejs, TailwindCss, Alpinejs.
- Dev env & Workflow: Docker, Git/Gitlab, Scrum.

01/2019 - present

Laayoune, Morocco

Freelancer Software Engineer

Elsahariano

Missions:

- Integration of 8 payment methods in an existing reservation system (Amanpay, Redsys, Cashplus, Payzon, and 4 local methods)
- Corrections and evolution of an existing intranet.
- Participation in the development of a reservation system
- Participation in the development of a mobile application

Tech Stack:

- Back end development: PHP, Laravel, Codeigniter, MySQL, PHPUnit, Python, Selenium.
- Front end development: Vuejs, TailwindCss.
- Mobile: React Native, IONIC 4
- Pycharm, PHPStorm, Intellij idea, Git/Github

05/2019 - 07/2019

Marrakesh, Morocco

FullStack Software Developer Java (Spring / Angular) - Intern

1 Minute Script 🛮

Mission:

• Development and design of a Web / Mobile application for the automation of inventory.

Tech Stack:

 JavaEE, JHipster, Spring Boot, Spring REST, Spring Security, JPA / Hibernate, Angular, IONIC 3

06/2018 - 01/2019

Marrakesh, Morocco E

FullStack Software Developer - Full Time

Emerging Business Factory - Pxlabs ☑

Missions:

- Development and improvement of applications/websites.
- Corrections and evolution of existing sites.
- Development and Maintenance of Hybrid Mobile Applications
- Development of the Front-End area of the OHM platform
- Participation in the development of an e-learning platform

Tech Stack:

- Back end development: PHP, Laravel, Symfony, MySQL.
- Front end development: Bootstrap, Vuejs, Jquery.
- Mobile Hybrid: IONIC 3
- CMS: WordPress
- PhpStorm, Git/Gitlab, Scrum, Slack/Trello

09/2017 - 2019

Marrakesh, Morocco

Fullstack Software Developer - Full Time

SEOCOM ☑

Missions:

- Development and Maintenance of applications / websites.
- Development of an e-commerce website
- Design / Development of an application for the management of a medical clinic
- Design / Development and Deployment of an application for the management of an insurance agency

Tech Stack:

- Back end development (PHP, Laravel, MySQL).
- Front end development (html/css, Bootstrap, Vuejs, Jquery).

06/2017 - 07/2017

Laayoune, Morocco

Software Developer - Intern

OCP Group ☑

Mission:

• Design and development of a desktop application for the management of purchases/orders/ suppliers/invoices.

Tech Stack:

• DotNet (C#), SqlServer, DotNetBar, CrystalRapport

SKILLS

Programming

PHP, JS, Java, Python, Typescript

Backend

Laravel, Symfony, JavaEE, Spring & JSF

Versioning tools & Devops, Unit. Tests

Git/Gitlab, Docker, PHPUnit, JUnit

Mobile Developpement

IONIC 4, (Flutter: beginner level)

Databases

MySql, Oracle (PL/Sql)

Frontend

Angular, Vuejs, Nuxt.js, TailwindCss, Bootstrap

Agile methodology

Scrum

Sys. Design & Soft. Engineering concepts

UML, Merise, Design patterns & Solide principles

AWARDS

09/2019 Award of Excellence in Bachelor's Degree 2018-2019

University Cadi Ayyad, Faculty of Sciences Semlalia in Marrakech

Field of study: Computer Sciences.

Option: Web Programming & Technologies.

Degree : Bachelor's Degree. **Promotion:** 2018-2019.

LANGUAGES

Arabic French
Native Intermediate

English

Intermediate